what's up everybody it's me the host of
the junkyard love podcast captain
america's great auntie
auntie america
man i haven't done one of these in a
while welcome it's great to uh great to
be coming through the airwaves to y'alls
um i just wanted to do like a little
couple little announcements a little
what's been going on in my life um and a
little intro to this episode so if you
want to just get right into the episode
um tell me to screw off and just skip a
few bars ahead yo
you will know the difference when you
hear the intro so just for a couple
minutes though um
these episodes that i'm posting are a
few months back that they were recorded
um
i have not been recording as many
episodes lately i record a lot of like
solo cast stuff just me kind of
processing talking to the camera or
whatever but i certainly don't post off
that some of it is a bit mad um so
other than that i haven't been doing too
many guests lately so these episodes
that are coming out are from um a few
months back so just a heads up on that
if there's any anything in the context
that seems like well that was a while
ago to have that perspective it's
because it was a little bit ago
um
but they don't it doesn't really change
it actually i i was thinking that that
would be kind of like sloppy and that
would suck and that would make the
episodes uninteresting but when i listen
back i'm reminded that podcasts a lot of
these conversations are so timeless you
know it's not like a news network where
um you know watching yesterday's news is
like uninteresting watching last week's
watching last month it's like this is a
waste of my time podcast conversations
are way different like there's there's
i'm 22 minutes in with this episode that
you're about about to listen to with
micah and
um there's already so many little gems
so many little wonderful golden nuggets
of information and like conversational
bits that uh you know it's that same
stuff that makes me fall in love with
with podcasting and uh what what got me
into like listening to long-form
conversations
is those little nuggets of gold that
someone like accidentally says or they
repeat or you know whatever the
conversation the conversation leads to
kind of an epiphany-ish point and for
the listener it's something that can
like really set a little light bulb off
really give you that aha moment and
those aha moments are
cream of the crop i love him i love him
aha moments so yeah we've already got
those going don't even worry about the
gap
um
to
the future of the podcast um i'm going
to i'm going to keep going i i was
actually thinking of pausing the podcast
like making an announcement or trying to
like
i keep i keep forgetting it's not really
a business for me you know it's like i
don't have to do certain things i'm
really just
this is kind of like my life blog you
know it's growing as i'm growing it's
going as i'm going
when i first started this podcast
it was you know i had basically my own
at-home studio like this dope recording
studio setup that um i could have people
in person
and i could like make a day of it they
could come over we could hang out we
could do a workout we could go to the
tap house down the road we could go to
the bar we could make some music we
could you know smoke drink like
basically have like a day with these
people and then have a conversation um
or have a conversation then a day and i
just this is this so this isn't the same
thing for me you know now i'm like
talking to people who are experts and um
very smart people and you know it's
different because i gotta kind of learn
how to connect with people through zoom
you know and and um it's been cool
because i didn't have a lot of faith in
it at the beginning but some of these
episodes are like man this is actually
such good [__] i'm able to connect with
these people just the same in a sense so
i'm just adjusting to it being different
you know and um tomorrow actually marks
a year since i've been living here in
austin texas um
and this whole last year i haven't
i haven't been like too
full steam ahead with the podcast you
know because i'm just trying to get my
grounding in life again you know uh
being in a relationship for 10 years
you know being living in the same place
my whole life you know having these same
routines having these same friends
everything changed for me you know like
i moved away from the hometown kobe
changed a lot of a lot of things for me
everything changed you know for a lot of
people not just me so
that's what this kind of whole last year
has been is
just kind of finding my footing figuring
out what i want i'm certainly not there
i'm still kind of exploring i'm still
like learning about myself i'm still
learning about this place i'm living in
now
um
so yeah i'm gonna the way i'm gonna do
the podcast is just authentically you
know i'm just i'm not gonna try to plan
it i i've never really done the whole
post wednesday at this time because
that's the most time for the algorithm
like hashtag this like i
any clicky thumbnail that i've that i've
made i've like done it almost as a
parody you know i i don't play the games
of trying to win the podcast thing or
trying to be a podcaster you know what i
mean like i i just
i just want to do this thing i just want
to share this corner of this thing that
i do and just like give it to people
here it is you know
if something comes of it i'm not one to
to you know run away from opportunity
but
i try not to turn this into something
that it's not you know so this is kind
of just my life blog you know i'm just
trying to be real and try to
share my perspective as my perspective
grows and changes and and life grows and
changes with it and you know i i'm
grateful for any listener and
if anything i have to offer is of value
um or even uh you know
worthwhile to spend your time listening
to that's pretty that's pretty amazing
to me that's pretty cool i'm i'm
grateful for that so
anyway this episode
we're about to get into it's with micah
it's super great i'm still writing up
the description so make sure you uh you
know glance through that and see what
you can find out of it micah is quite
wonderful i always love our
conversations um
it's a good one man it's a good one the
podcasts are going to keep coming the
episodes are going to keep coming if you
are sitting in the uh
in my email inbox or you're sitting in
my um
uh
podcast pod match inbox i'm sorry i'll
get to you i've got
things going on things i'm sorting out
things are not sorting out i will get to
you so thanks for your patience there i
have so many cool guests i have this
opportunity to
like basically people send their bios to
me now
and they say here's what i do here's
what i know here's what i talk about
here's who i am like would you like to
have me as a guest on your podcast and
they're all so good they're all like i'm
like oh yeah i'd be honored um and then
i deal with this imposter syndrome where
i'm like well this person talking to me
so you know it's cool i'm gonna do it um
i'm gonna get more of these people on
here so hang tight if you are in that
bunch
um
otherwise i'm pretty active these days a
little bit more on tick-tock lately
although i might go through like a rage
quit and quit off tick tock we'll see a
little bit on tick tock but mostly on
instagram instagram is usually where you
can find me um usually where you can get
a hold of me the quickest too i'm kind
of like terrible responding in other
areas
all things i'm plowing through and
working through right we've all got our
baggage eh so on instagram check me out
on instagram jacob from the internet um
if you need any audio i'm still an audio
guy too i do djing audio creative stuff
if you like any of the poetry or rap or
any of the the
you know
kind of garbage stuff that i make that's
just fun for me to make um
check out my instagram jacob from the
internet and reach out to me on there so
thanks for listening hope everybody has
a good day if you're listening to this
right now uh
breathe through your nose man breathe
out let go of the tension that's in your
shoulders let go the tension that's in
your face become aware of your five
senses
think about the feeling in your hands
feel the clothes against your skin
let go of the pressure in your chest in
your back
breathe out
let's go
enjoy the episode with micah knowledge
is power
[Music]
is
hi
how are you
i'm good how are you i'm not bad at all
i'm doing pretty good
i tried
on my laptop and it wasn't working so
i'm on my phone so oh dang i it looks
actually pretty clear it looks fine
yeah cool yeah it's always an issue
dealing with the technical difficulties
of zoom i had a podcast yesterday
morning that was
like in the end i'm not even sure if i'm
able to use it because the the audio was
just like so wavering in and out she was
coming to me from like across the world
i forget where but somewhere else
and so it was just like such a delay
that i might not be able to use the
audio
that is a bummer
but it's exciting that you're getting to
a podcast with people from like a wider
area
yeah it feels weird like the uh the guy
that i interviewed earlier today
like i was giddy the whole time it was
he was literally just basically somebody
that i'd read his books or i'd watch his
stuff on youtube and just be like super
obsessed with it so for me to actually
be able to sit down and like pick his
brain was super super cool it's uh yeah
it's a cause i told you about that um
the pod match
it's it's basically this company that
i'm working with that like hooks me up
with potential podcast guests did i tell
you about that
no i didn't know about that oh yeah so
it's um they reached out like they
probably have you know based off of
people who have a good amount of
episodes or listeners or whatever it is
they reach out send me an email said
check out the thing and it's basically a
um it's like tinder for podcast guests
and podcast hosts so they use like ai
algorithms that match up like potential
interests and like i just filled out
like an extensive bio and it pairs me
with people they send me a message say
hey here's what i do here's what i study
here's what i'm all about you want to
have me on the podcast and i could say
yes or no so it's pretty freaking cool
wow that certainly makes your job a
little bit easier it's outsourcing for
you so you can find guests that are
aligned with some of the topics you're
either missing or
you like to continually discuss
yeah yeah for real yeah it's it's been
pretty cool so far i like it um
okay well hey how are you my friend
what's what's been up what have you been
up to
um i've actually been like super bored
lately but
excited to start my new job when the
academic school year starts so
more or less i'm just kind of like
in a mental space thinking about that
kind of
imagining how i would like my space to
look um
brainstorming about what i want to put
on the walls trying to decide what like
mental health material is going to be
engaging and not tacky to high school
students
i'm realizing how difficult that's going
to be
and i'm like trying to
preemptively get a thick skin about you
know the amount of times i might hear
like that's stupid or i don't understand
that you know and have to think okay
like how do i
how do i re-address this given
the age group and the
what they
want aesthetically what they feel is
funny i don't know
right yeah like you don't want your your
high school students to roast you
well i just remember all the tacky
posters in school like when we were in
school like i will never get the mental
image out of like two specific ones out
of my head is the cat hanging from a
tree branch that says hanging
and um
like the it's like two i think it
probably female hands but holding hands
and one was a a white person one was a
black person and they were like the hand
of friendship has no color
or something like that
and i just i'm like they could really do
better with these posters like they're
trying to say a lot in a few words and
it's just not hidden everyone's just
looking at it and like
being like yeah sure okay you know it's
not
we're deeper than that so it's gonna be
interesting but
yeah i i love that you think about stuff
like that though too because i totally
would as well and i was also the type of
student to very i'd be very cognizant of
all that [__] that's on the wall i'd be
like reading it instead of listening to
the teacher so it is cool like to think
that you can
even
think about like the the
the
like the first junk hair love studio
that i had in the basement in castle
rock like i wanted it to be this vibe
that you walk into like you walk in and
you're like
you're you're high in openness like it's
very visual you know there's a lot of
like creativity just right when you walk
in sort of thing because you know you
want to spark that in other people too
and it's just how i like to exist so
yeah being able to create your own
teacher cave that's going to spark
something within you know the students
and have them inspired when they walk in
in some sort of way that's awesome oh
absolutely i mean
marie fondo and everyone else in the
design world would agree with me like
setting up a space to look like what
it's intended to feel like is so
important
and i feel like one of the biggest
things i'm coming up against already is
like a technical issue
the lights in my what's going to be my
room specifically
have not turned off since april
like we literally cannot turn them off
the control pad doesn't do anything they
are just there there's like nine of them
and they're the bright led
long bulbs
and they just have they've just been on
for you know however many months that is
now and we feel about that
and i'm like this is not a therapeutic
space like brights are the opposite of
therapeutic every therapeutic space i've
ever been to is like it's natural light
or it's lamp light or it's dim lighting
it's a space to come in relax breathe
kind of feel like you're in a movie
theater when you take that breath before
the movie starts and you're like oh yes
i'm about to dive into a whole different
world so the whole nine bright leds that
won't turn off thing i'm
currently trying to figure out a
solution for that that i
have more control over because i'm like
this will not do like my eyes cannot do
this either
yeah yeah it almost is like it's like a
factory setting versus a like a
welcoming setting i think accent
lighting is is like so huge for for
i'm gonna use the word vibes i'm sorry
but
it really is big for vibes
you try not to use that word but it's
the only thing that suffices for a lot
of things
i know i i'm i'm such a hippie i find a
way to use the word vibes wherever i can
so
see it works because we get what we're
saying right um
so
we
we had a list of uh potential topics to
talk about i like that you jotted those
down um because when i when i read over
it i was like oh yeah yeah that's dope
uh so we
for any listeners this is the second
episode that i've had with micah our
first episode if i recall correctly um
it was
i'm pretty sure yeah yeah
you came over and i was having a bad
depression day um and i pretty much just
like told you that and then we kind of
started from there and talked about it
and it was a beautiful conversation so
if you want more of her bio or to hear
any other conversations with us listener
check that episode out i don't remember
the episode episode number you can
scroll
um
but yeah mikey we've been uh going on on
walks before i had moved we were going
on walks of the lake and we enjoyed the
conversation we'd always just kind of
like pick each other's brains what's
going on in our life right now and
just
i don't know we always had good ass
conversations so i'm happy you're here
i'm happy to be here it was episode 36
i remember because i have a memory for
numbers also it was super fun for me so
it's one of the things i like to
think about um
i've definitely been missing walks with
you it's not
easy to find a walking partner i guess
i think
what people underestimated is like
you really are alone with that person
for however long the walk is and if you
don't like talking to them you're like
i don't want to do it again
like
by myself if i'm looking for you know
silence but
yeah i miss that i do have
kind of a walking partner right now
she's someone i used to work with at
toodle school um has really refreshing
ideas and we have great conversations
but
it was nice to have a male perspective
on a lot of stuff
i do i'm grounded by a lot of female
friends and so
it's not easy to replace
an open-minded
male mindset in calyx county
yeah yeah i mean i get it's it's funny i
i end up resonating a lot with females
more i mean it's probably just because i
grew up my you know
major years of life zero through seven
or zero through eight or whatever i was
surrounded by three older sisters and a
mom and a bunch of other females so it's
just like very natural for me to be in
touch with my more feminine side and so
i feel like i resonate with with females
well enough um and then it's it is it's
interesting it's it's interesting and
cool uh to
look at kind of the different sides of
ourselves that we get when we show up
with different people like if i'm with a
bunch of dudes like you know drinking
bud lights i'm gonna be like a different
kind of virgin corner of myself than i
am when when you and i are talking about
like you know introspective masculine
versus feminine things while we're
walking the lake
absolutely yep we all have different
i feel like you know when talking about
people who are uh
multi-personalitied in some way whether
that's by diagnosis or just something
people pick up on about them i feel like
we're not really being fair i think
everyone is kind of a chameleon and it
doesn't necessarily mean it's a bad
thing we just have different
modes different
different personality types within us
that we want to
interact with we want others to interact
with just depending on the setting
i think we're kind of sometimes we're
harsh about people who have a lot of
like big personalities or different like
attributes because we're like well which
one are you really and
like all of them
yeah exactly anyone with bodies any
personality type is all the personality
types they embody
yeah yeah yeah well we want to like
pinpoint who we are like we're this
person like it's our report card here's
here's our attributes and here's who we
are and here's uh what we do and what we
don't do and it's like we're so much
more fluid than that in every situation
we're different um after we eat certain
foods we're different after we drink
certain beverages we're different in the
morning we're different than at the
night like we're we're a fluid
experience not this definitive i think
that we want to
i think that when we're othering people
it makes us feel good to
know what they are like it's like like
if it maybe it's a survival thing you
know a survival thing of the ego
because you know we need to know oh
that's a lie that brown thing over there
is a lion and lions could eat me so i
know that that's bad
um or oh that's a deer and i could eat
that deer that's good you know so we
label things and then we want to kind of
put them into the boxes or put them into
what it means to us and it makes us feel
like we have it done okay that's good or
bad now i can move on with my life so we
as much as we want to label each other
and like
say that we are this this single-pointed
thing it's just not the truth we're
fluid we're all chameleons some of us
more chameleons than not some of us are
vastly unaware of how chameleon we are
but uh yeah i i like i feel like as i
get older and as i see the different
sides of myself
as i compare like my
my personhood of who i am when i'm in
like a customer service setting versus
who i am when i'm like a weirdo artist
saying poetry in the woods
i'm like what the [__] like i'm just i'm
two very very different people but i'm
actually just both of them i'm all of
them you know
right i think it's i mean everyone likes
i don't know if everyone maybe that's a
bold statement but i think most people
enjoy kind of like dressing up
in like physical form and i feel like
trying on different personalities even
if we don't know if it's one of ours yet
it's just our way of like seeing like
how we'd like to grow and where like
trying out new words or language um
depending on what's trending or just
funny [__] that we think
in our head and seeing how we feel like
when we actually say it to other people
and what the reaction is and we're like
do i like that does that sound like me
like we all kind of have our own idea of
like what's on or off brand for us i
think in the general sense
um
but the other thing i was thinking about
as you were talking is that i feel like
the universe has a way of every time you
think you kind of know who you are and
who you like to interact with
it will send someone else into your life
that totally corroborates that line of
thinking you're like oh so you don't
like this type of person
well have you met so and so who embodies
all these things that you think you
don't get along with but
you guys share one common hobby that
makes you interact in a way that is
exciting and new and then all of a
sudden you're like wait okay so i guess
i like people um that are representative
of this political party or this
religious denomination or
have this job i think along with the
labeling is that we want to sometimes
check people out because that would just
be easier instead of
admitting that we are more alike than we
are different and if there's even just
like like when you watch movies and
people get stranded and these people
typically they set up to where the two
people that are stranded don't like each
other
and then they eventually like each other
or they form a romantic protection and
if you
didn't watch the whole movie and if you
just saw the first 10 minutes in the
last 10 minutes you'd be like no way
that's not real that doesn't happen but
it happens more in regular
life than we want to admit that we
really judge someone from the moment we
see them and we're like oh yeah we
probably won't be friends
and then give yourself you know a couple
weeks couple months couple years and all
of a sudden there's someone that you
really come to respect whether or not
you believe what they believe
because that means no one's off the
table really you can be friends with
anyone you can find common ground with
anyone
and i think that's way more exciting
than the idea of
well if we don't share the same views on
this aspect of life then
it will never be like
i know i've told people as like a
general line before i don't know if
everyone gets it but i'm like
i don't want a romeo and juliet
like never in my life do i want a romeo
brilliant situation where
two families two groups of friends
two sets of co-workers whatever it may
be just literally can't get along
and it's like why not
like
why don't you want to get along
what is so much more interesting about
the drama or the gossip that's happening
that you like and you find more inviting
than the idea of we disagree on things
that's fine we're allowed to have our
own opinion
and then we let it rest i don't know i
just think that story is so chaotic and
dumb like i just i really don't get it
no it's like
great
english literature or something but i'm
just like i just
chaotic like so many things could have
been different and i think they would
have been just fine if they would have
just let go of
the weight of other people's
perspectives on everything
yeah 100 i mean they didn't even get to
hang out that long like they ended up
like yeah roman and julia loved each
other but they ended up dying within
like was a couple months or something
like wasn't it not very long like i mean
like what like why not choose something
different you don't really have to die
for the person you could
learn how to live with them how about
that
it is it is interesting uh i i really
like
you know
it does make us feel better when we when
we have someone else's identity like
when we know we think we know what they
are but it's also i think i think about
how ramdas says we're all just walking
each other home we're we're all just
walking and one another home
because it's so true
yeah
i mean someone sometimes the strangest
people show up but if we just are
accepting of the moment we're like that
was actually helpful
i needed that
yeah yeah like how is this person here
to make i mean think about like the word
triggering you know so something gets
triggered within you you could you could
choose to be like oh i don't like that
person that made me feel this way they
they made me feel bad i don't like them
you know or is it
ah
they're pointing out something in me
that i could grow on they're pointing
out something in me that seems to be
solid and i'm actually a fluid being who
could learn about that huh should i lean
into this more you know it's uh
i think when you look at it as
you know this is part of the life
curriculum is spiritual growth you know
when someone comes into your life
and you can look at it as like you know
maybe they're taking you off maybe
they're they're triggering you maybe
they're uh you know bringing out sides
in you that you don't want to admit like
if you're like oh i'm not an angry
person but you find yourself getting
angry because of this person maybe it's
kind of like ah i was bullshitting
myself okay well that's humbling now
let's learn what the world is trying to
teach me through this person
oh for real
absolutely i i think we too like
the things that we really feel like
guilt and shame around
also kind of come with anger a lot of
the time those are the things that we're
like i'm not i'm not defensive or angry
about this because if i am that means i
have to admit
that i actually embody this like the
only way we get defensive is we also see
a problem where they problem
otherwise it would not bother us if
someone off said something off the wall
about us that we don't believe about
ourselves in some capacity like
okay that's frustrating feel that way
and you're directing that hostility
towards me but
and the general you know term events
like it doesn't affect me
because i see myself well enough show
it's not true but if it's even
there's even a little smidgen of feeling
like that actually embodies truth you're
gonna hear that and go wow
you're like i don't need to listen to
you anymore because you hurt my feelings
i'm gonna go
but we should be you're right we should
be thinking about those things and
deeper like we don't do it in front of
them or say anything to them but we take
it inside ourselves be like okay why did
i feel that way like
my body intuitively resonated with an
angry emotion to that
something's not aligned some some part
of me is like this is actually there's
truth in that
and can i fix it
is it something i haven't healed yet
yeah i mean
sorry you go
no no no you're fine feel free to
interrupt me if i interrupt you um no it
really is this uh
uh
i don't know it's like growth mindset
versus fixed mindset it's like i am this
person and you are that person or
it's
you're you're pointing out something
that this interaction between this other
being and me as a being
is part of my growth like it really is
i i mean we've talked about it on the
podcast sometimes before um i've just
talked about it just growth mindset
versus fixed mindset and it really is
like it could flip your whole
perspective on life when you see life as
some sort of video game where you're
just trying to collect coins and you're
just trying to like whatever happens to
you is just part of the level right now
it's just just where you got like you
don't take it personally you don't you
don't pout about it you don't be like
i'm not playing this game anymore it's
like
the thing that life has handed you is
what you're here here to deal with you
know and sometimes it's super unfair and
sometimes it's painful and sometimes it
hurts and sometimes it's um
um
you know
triggering again but i think i think
leaning into it you know it's like
as many times as i've been stuck and
i've been stag and i've been uh the
arbiter of my own pain
you know
like
as i get older i just learn oh yeah okay
i guess it did have to be that way for
it to be this way and look at all that
i've learned um here's mistakes i'm not
gonna make again because i did learn
from those things instead of like
striking away from them
so
yeah it's uh life is life is truly a
journey life is a video game right it's
just the easiest explanation i mean
as soon as we had all these crazy
off-the-wall events happen in the last
two or three years and all these things
that some people believe were real and
like
something i just i have so many thoughts
of reality in my brain right now but
something i like to think about is that
i don't particularly subscribe to any
sort of like denomination or anything
but i'm so down with hypotheticals for
any circumstance and any religion any
story i think every story that ever
existed whether it's fiction or
non-fiction is a parable it's it it's
intended to
define some sort of moral aspect ethical
aspect of the human condition and if you
do or don't respond to it um
the implications that can be positive
and negative in both respects and so
when you think about things like that i
think it takes the heat and the
triggering off a lot of the religious
documents if you're not religious if you
just look at it like it's a parable or a
storyline
without trying to think oh people
actually believe this you know and if
you don't
it actually becomes kind of interesting
um and something that i think people
don't ruminate on a law about jesus is
that he was not popular
like he
he had a following but it would be
similar to that of like
someone who believed in aliens prior to
this year you know they have a following
or like sasquatchers they have a
following they have a group of friends
but they're not exactly popular you know
you don't have the greater percent of
like 30 or more of the world or the
country backing them and being like no
this is fact and i would i would put my
life on the line for this and so
i just after the last couple of years
we've had i think a lot of those groups
that have been you know kind of like
made fun of maybe not to their face
they're
turning corners now we're like okay so
we don't know what's under the ocean so
government's releasing documents the
aliens have existed and we've covered it
up okay
i just feel like if everyone's brains
aren't kind of like having many
explosions on a weekly basis i'm just
not sure how because i feel like all
that's happened in the last years it's
time to like show us
anything is possible maybe it's not
possible right now maybe it was possible
a hundred thousand years ago maybe it's
possible in the future
but i don't really think anything's off
the table anymore
something i've thought for a long time
is that if an idea can exist in my head
as i try to come up with like my
multi-million dollar idea to like patent
and just like become insta-rich like the
guy who made pool noodle you know it's
like it's just simple [__] you just
gotta figure it out and be the first one
there and do it well
and patent it
um
but
if i think of an idea in my head it's
because it already exists
not like i can't do it differently
or someone else can't do it
differently i just think that the ideas
that we have the stories the creatures
that we have in our heads the demons all
of it it's like if it can exist in our
mind
it already exists
in some capacity it already exists i
don't think we can think of things that
aren't
already relevant
i don't know i just i kind of got in
this only trip about like new ideas
don't exist like they don't come from
color you don't think of a new
island that no one noticed on a map
before um
it's just now about realizing that
we are in kind of a video game setting
that if you want to redesign some aspect
of the video game or you want to find
some
hidden gem or an easter egg like you
absolutely can but i don't think
anything new is to be
like coming out of the woodwork it's
just about recognizing the little things
that are
behind the 5d 4d 3d mindset and every
time you
upgrade
you
understand and see more stuff i don't
know if that made sense but
no i i i followed go on
just ah just the brain explosions over
the last years and
i wish there were more places to talk
about it openly i wish the conversation
was more centered around what everything
everything that is possible positive
now um
and less centered around the
fear-mongering of the virus and
it's terrible what's happened no doubt
sickness is real illness is real
um
but i don't i don't understand why
people want to focus so much on
the fear aspect of it
instead of taking things a new direction
well i mean we we love to know we love
to have stable ground for sure we we
love to we love our illusions you know
especially in the western world we like
we like thinking that somebody is
steering the ship we like thinking that
like
somebody there's somebody who knows
everything and yeah this is a hundred
percent true and they this exactly what
we read in the books is exactly how it
goes but uh you know you know
sorry news flash that's not how things
go um eric weinstein talks about um
he presents he talks very elegantly on
um
basically kind of like conspiracy
theorists um and kind of i think he
calls them cranks cranks and kooks or
something like that like he uh he has
some there's some sort of abbreviation
that he has that somebody can look up i
don't remember um but but he does he
points out kind of you know especially
in today's age and especially with the
internet um
we can't just
continue to completely disregard stuff
that's on the fringe we can't just say
like oh that guy's a crank or that guy
that guy's a kook like he's a crazy
person like
we can't disregard people like that
anymore because if we look at history
how many crazy people how many crazy
people
like at the beginning everyone's like
what are you dude you're nuts and it
ends up
answering our reality later and also at
the same time not just people if we take
it over to ideas like you were talking
about micah
think about like
like how closely knit our past sci-fi
movies and the sci-fi books in the pop
culture are now our actual reality
like
ideas and
and
reaches like where where it's hey this
thing might be possible here's this
crazy idea i don't have all the in
between i i can't show my work yet
because it hasn't presented itself yet
you know i can't show the in-between but
here's the answer here's this idea
it can't be disregarded because i feel
like history has shown continuously that
the crazy ideas the conspiracy theorists
the the whatever and right now we're
literally at a point we have no idea
what to do with this alien thing like
this should break everything if we
really actually sat down and said all
right we are as a culture accepting it
like new york times
cnn fox and like any of the
the corporate press the the people who
control what we all think about in the
the mass propaganda but just everybody
has pretty much accepted now
there's these things
i don't know if we're fully saying yes
it's aliens or are we just at a point of
saying
here's the thing that happened and we
don't have the technology for it so
like
but but what so so how do we like accept
this how do we bring it into our actual
conversations i don't
i don't know if i have like a great
answer for that i feel like
i
i feel like i may be one of the few
people who loves hypotheticals because
that way of thinking that line of
thinking
allows me to accept a lot of stuff i
don't understand and some of it may be
stuff that i don't necessarily want to
dive in and do the research on i'm
comfortable letting other people do that
or hearing like hearsay on it and other
stuff will be like no i'm going to get
to the bottom of this but
either way i think just approaching
anything
that's
happening with like a curious mind
is a lot easier than
hearing things and immediately
disregarding it like regardless of who's
recording it if it's on social media
news
science
no articles um
just looking at it going
what if that were the case
like what would that mean in other
respects or how could i find out how
you know realistic that is or
i don't know i don't know if there's a
good answer for that
but it's a good question
yeah i mean i think oh it'd be just
remaining in the open mind or the you
know beginner's mind of uh well i don't
for sure know you know i
that's kind of how i think all the time
i don't like all the crazy [__] that i
talk about it's it's all
like at the end of it i'm i have a
question mark at the end of everything i
say i feel like you know
yeah i don't know that's fascinating
though like isn't this interesting to
you that's all i'm saying you know
we we really love
arguing about the truth and like when
you're talking about religion i love
that because
i think that's where a lot of our
conversation inevitably goes we shut
down as soon as we hear like oh you're a
christian
or yo europe whatever
like
like instead of
oh oh okay so so the stories that that
you read and you understand um what
happened in this way that makes you feel
the feeling of joy in community and love
and that's how you access
faith that's how you access hope that's
how you know
there's all these different emotions and
experiences that we can all experience
we all have different stories across the
whole world of course we all grew up you
know in in were created into what we are
from vastly different environments and
different places all across the big
world so
we're all pointing to the same thing
we're just we just have different
stories of
of of of the finger you know the the
hand that's pointing you know maybe it's
a different color but we're pointing at
the same thing right you know
exactly how
i mean how would we all come to the same
conclusion
the intent was that we were all designed
with different minds different
personality traits different
different ways of thinking um
a different tolerances for different
things it's like how i mean
realistically i mean we can't
we can't get the world to agree on like
what the most like health beneficial
fruit or vegetable is and that should
come down to science realistically we
could test for those things and people
still wouldn't agree
on it and so how could we agree on
something as big as
how we got here
why
what do we do here what's most important
to do while we're here is anything
important to do while we're here and so
there's no way there's no way we would
ever get to the same answer but i
definitely think that we are like you
said we're all on the same track we're
all in the same kind of idea mindset of
there's there's something
i mean how can we prove it
i don't know because that's
science can't all science does i feel
like all science does is
disproves things science doesn't prove
things i guess i shouldn't even take
back my last statement science disproves
things
and then that whatever
seems like the most likely outcome is
the new idea of what happens
and tell someone just that
yeah yeah because it's it because i mean
i think that's
i don't i feel like it's less a
mechanism of science itself and more of
a mechanism of what science feels
for us as a society you know like it's
it's our way of making sense
i do think
that having it be the only way
that we make sense like we kind of
disregard anything anything else that's
not like if you don't have scientific
studies if you don't have uh
peer-reviewed science backing it it's
we're not accepting it as truth we're
not even going to like mess with it i
guess there does have to be some you
know
logical way of of existing and making
decisions on a large scale so we do have
to have science science is super
important right but i think there is
more there's more to this whole thing
that's going on than in science um
yeah i
yeah it's interesting because because i
um like the the last guy that i talked
to uh we it was really cool to talk to
him because he
he is a scientist
um and he does or
he i don't know he has like a phd and
and uh
like i'm totally spacing it uh i'll have
to give his bio when when i type it out
but um he was able to still question
like he wasn't like very
only black and white thinker he was very
um
philosophical as well you know but he's
also a science and he studies important
stuff so
i don't know man we are at this edge um
i i think that social media and um the
internet like you know youtube
especially think about how much youtube
has progressed my like levels of
consciousness and what i understand and
how i perceive the world
i think that also changes what we're at
the edge of you know like i would say on
the podcast the iphone came out in 2007.
that's not that freaking long ago so
over this course of the last you know
whatever whatever many years less than
20 years we have
like
so much new knowledge like so many
different evolutions of ourselves that
are being so many skins shed you know
it's like every month we believe
something profoundly and the next month
we're like
i got a little more information i sat on
that a little bit longer i don't know
that i believe that fully right now and
it's it's this fun thing but it is like
it's jarring you know our society is
going through like
there's so much new [__] there's so much
potential there's so much mixture of our
sci-fi with our reality that like we we
are now accepting aliens and we're like
oh that's a cool like
let's scroll the next tick tock
yeah
no
you really did i've just that
that number knowing that it's
14 years
is that right
i can't until seven
no 1349.
but
how many social media outlets have come
and gone and some that have kind of like
come back and forth um
that i don't know like we haven't even
been attached to any one of them for
more than a couple years and even then
there's always competing ones like
coming out every couple of months um
i don't know that fact just got me that
was weird like i know i've had facebook
since 2009 that's probably the longest
standing one i've had
um
and they own instagram they own all of
it
oh it's yeah yeah [__] kellogg's owns
all of these too and then shell owns
kellogg's i think it's all just so
intertwined at this point
oh my gosh they know what they're doing
um
one of the things i thought about
through the course of what you were
saying is that
the the reason why i made the statement
that the universe sends people in who's
going to kind of contradict like what
you thought you didn't like or people
you thought you didn't like
um the friend that i go walking with now
i thought i had an idea of who she was
and i had no idea she was christian um
i've known her for
a year and a half two years she's never
brought this up and so i just assumed
she wasn't given some other aspects of
her personality and just
how uh
how she just operates and speaks and i'm
like oh she's not religious like i feel
like i can definitely
observe that about her and then on her
most recent walk she comes out to me
about her faith and her come to jesus
moment and i'm like
i was kind of like a deer in headlights
i was like what the heck
and i'm trying to think about all the
things i've talked about with her that i
felt comfortable saying because i didn't
expect to run into like a religious wall
at all with her
and then i had to just refocus and be
like but think about it like she never
has
become defensive about anything you've
ever said or done in the past and that
really speaks to her
having her own ideas and not needing to
interject
and how cool that actually is and now
she's opening it more about her faith
and feels comfortable to do so and i
need to respond in a respectful way as
well
and what we kind of came to realize is
that both of us have some really radical
views
not exactly the same but still radical
on how we came to be and like what the
storyline is and
how like she agreed with me on like
every book being like a parable she's
like i completely agree and we talked
about how
how could the bible be an exact
realistic factual version of what
happened when everything is coming from
someone's perspective like what we know
about perspective today is the same as
it was way back then
if one person is getting to dictate and
write the story
how is it accurate
because
they are part of the human condition
they were human when they wrote it
they can't they can't speak the absolute
god-given truth
they're a human dictating a human
experience and so
we talked about how she said she wants
to see like what's in the bag again and
all the stuff that's coming out because
she's like i want to know more about
these people who were
determined evil or bad in religious text
like they obviously have their own story
as to why they did what they did and if
it even happened the way it happened
um and so
i don't know i felt like that like i
wish i could have that conversation
to share with you and full because
refreshing for me to be like
the universe is showing me that i need
to be having more of these conversations
with people who are
considering themselves about christians
about catholics like
they're
they are capable of having mature
conversations
now the people i'm running into when i
didn't feel that was a possibility for
me back in school
and so i was
look i enjoyed it but i was shook
because i'm like wait a minute yeah
yeah
what i'm used to but it's great because
it's going to give me more of a
interest in talking to my own family
who's religious about
what exactly they believe and why they
believe it
right right yeah i mean it's it's it's
again we're walking each other home and
sometimes we're going to trigger each
other but it's not such a bad thing you
know it's a
you know i think that
and maybe this is a perception that when
we were growing up that we just never
really challenged but i was kind of
thinking about how when i was younger
there was this natural inclination
i wasn't like against religion i wasn't
like um like
like get away from me christians or or
you know whatever but there was a
background task of like
like you do feel closed off instantly
like the second someone says they're
christian you don't feel like they're
going to be able to like listen to what
your ideas are you do feel very other
than them um
but but as i get older and actually have
conversations with people about their
about their beliefs it's more of uh i i
find it to be more like that like like
you said where you guys are open to talk
about whatever and then she shares
her experience with you like here's what
here's how i got to this here was my
actual lived experience and you weren't
like sure that's not true like you were
you were probably listening you know you
were listening
and saying
you know oh oh wow okay so that was your
experience well here's my experience to
reach those same sort of things you know
so i guess what i'm trying to say is
maybe um
maybe people are growing more open to
discuss these sorts of things because
we're realizing that it doesn't have to
be an argument it doesn't we don't have
to wall off from each other
it doesn't mean that like the person who
we're talking to if we're not sharing
their belief that they're thinking the
whole time like you're going to burn in
hell you're going to burn in hell like
because you're you don't believe what i
do um
i i think that
i don't know i i feel a little i feel a
little scarred by um by
if anybody who's listening who's
christian i hope you understand that i
this is all love i'm i'm just talking
about specific um uh things things in in
my life but i don't i don't dislike
christians or anything like that um
i was kind of scared when i was younger
i was with um
one of the girls that dated in high
school and she i went with her family
and her grandparents to um to church i
think i went a couple times and one of
the times like i was so [__]
uncomfortable man because the
the pastor was started going um
i i mean basically i was convinced that
i was gonna burn in hell because i
didn't believe what he would he believe
i mean that's like what a lot of it was
was they were talking about what happens
to the people who don't believe what we
believe in this room you know him
assuming that everybody in that room has
the same belief um and so it kind of
like shirked me away from it but that
doesn't mean that that's how all
religions are that's how that all
religious people are like that all
spiritual people are like that again we
all have our
way of getting to some sort of
conclusion we all have our way of
experiencing these
inner
inner experiences like getting in touch
with our soul and our own mortality and
our own existence like these sorts of
things are compartmentalized into
religious text and religious talk a lot
of the times and
instead of trying to decipher who's
right and who's wrong and who's got the
truth
it's just like
what do you feel through the
conversation like what do you learn
through a conversation just be open and
discuss because i think you'll learn
that you're kind of talking about
kind of talking about the same thing you
know we're all
we're all pointing to to kind of the the
same thing we all just kind of have
different ways of getting there i don't
think we really need to argue over
what's 100
capital t truth or not unless
unless we're the ones writing books and
that's our job to do so and we're
getting paid to do it so
absolutely i
i just had a thought on it
oh my gosh am i seriously just gonna
like lose my mind right now
um
oh i was just thinking that you know i
think that
the way churches are changing a lot of
the time is for the better i mean i do i
have had similar experiences
um going to church and the one sermon i
go to was like the whole parliamental
concept and i'm like oh my god i'm
terrified like even if i was already
like i i was christian growing up and so
i already like asked to absolve my sins
and had already been dedicated as a baby
and still i mean sitting in those
sermons was terrifying i'm like okay i
have to do it again
like you know it's scary but i think the
way they're changing and shaping now is
awesome like
pastors and
people who are leading the service
breaking the mold by coming out as
openly gay openly transgender openly
these things that society hasn't even
fully accept yet that we're trying to
and i feel like the whole point of
everything is like maybe if we just keep
having people pop up and break the mold
like maybe they have to do things or
hide who they are for a little bit until
they get to a certain place but when
they come out as who they really are
they get to
really show people like okay so you
liked me when you thought that i was
straight i'm still the same person
except for now i'm coming out as openly
who i am inside
um and what my preference is for
romantic partners and you need to get
over it because i'm still the same
person you knew five minutes ago
i've just decided now is the time to be
more upfront about this one aspect of
who i am
and
i think it's awesome i think if we keep
having people in every industry in every
field and every religious denomination
breaking the mold showing up
and you know people starting to like
them and then they break the mold in
some way we just keep breaking the mold
over and over again
there will be no more molds
there will be no more boxes there will
be no more
of ways to label anyone that could be
exclusive or offensive
i feel like there's it doesn't serve a
purpose really to have
do we really need to walk into a certain
arena a certain place
a certain group club meeting community
and do we really have to show up with an
idea of like what we expect to see
i know our brain likes to do that our
brains are wired to seek out patterns
and we
think it's helpful for survival but i
think we've kind of passed that point
you know
we really can't
look at someone and dictate whether or
not they are a threat to us in our lives
and i think that maybe a conversation
people aren't ready to talk about we
want to blame certain groups of people
because some percentage of them has
acted
aggressively or angrily to things in
just a very uh
uncomfortable way um
but we can't still say that you know
that all people who've agreed with this
one idea or mindset
can't also have incredibly
kind and humanitarian morals in a whole
other way
yeah
do you think that we're like
do you think that we're like almost
traumatized by religion like we're in
this place of almost like a
post-religion spot in our world right
like it's not that long ago that we kind
of have been living with this you know
you know
god is dead um situation um and not that
everybody lives with it but but it is
interesting we are traumatized by it
like it's like
uh you know like if we were bit by a
snake when we were younger
you know we're going to be looking out
for snakes
when we're older or if i i've said this
one before if a guy with a snake on his
shirt
yells at you really loudly when you're
four years old you might be like
traumatized of snakes and so there might
be like some reciprocating uh or some
uh leftover
strange scarring or trauma when it comes
to religious talk or spiritual talk
because there's so many people that that
i know in me even just a couple just a
few years ago um where i'm just like i
you start talking about spiritual stuff
or religious stuff i'm like i'm not
listening bro
it's so so funny i think
i think i had to oh it triggered me but
it's the truth i had this moment this
train of thought probably
a year and a half and then my spiritual
journey but i'm like
i've denounced christianity for my life
so hard
just to find myself claiming i'm
spiritual
uh
that maybe is trending at first but now
i actually believe some of the things
that align with that and i am in her
own little religion again whether or not
i go to a place and i talk about it with
anyone but i'm like so funny
he named god what god is i decided god
is out
the universe sources
in literally just dude it's so funny
micah
we all we all something to believe in
and so
whether that is a human person or an
enigma or a concept or an idea or this
otherworldly being it's like
no i don't think i don't think any one
of us is walking around thinking
you know
we don't
subscribe to something higher or we
don't have respect for something that we
don't fully understand and can't fully
validate
so i don't know i just like i had to
really sit with myself about that i was
like how i was like i literally just i
went and found a new type of faith like
i was kind of
ambiguously faith driven for a few years
like high school you know i wasn't
really thinking about it and then
halfway through college i was like
i didn't feel like i had a lot of faith
and i didn't feel like i had a lot of
interest in certain things and then
incomes you know trending millennial
spiritual stuff and i like tarot cards
and i start buying crystals by the
dozens and i start looking into starseed
[__] and i'm like
sold
all right this way aligns with my
psychology stuff way more than anything
else i can be a behaviorist mindset and
be a spiritual
guru in my own respect and it's just
it's just funny but i
see i think your whole idea on trauma is
really it's spot on and it's interesting
because
if something that traumatized us shows
up in a
outfit
and a new vessel
we are not as traumatized until we
realize they embody the thing that
traumatized us before
so
i'm thinking of like people who find
themselves habitually in abusive
relationships
until that new person exhibits the
behaviors that that old abusive person
exhibits
you think you've got a good one
they have like that you
and you you keep going down that road
and until those behaviors pop up you
don't realize that you're going to
re-traumatize yourself by letting in the
same thing because it's put in a
different package every single time
if we can't physically recognize the
trauma right out of the gate we have an
opportunity to be traumatized if it
looks different
lessons will be repeated until learned
absolutely yeah damn yeah that's a i i
really like that eyes
i'm glad we stumbled into this area of
conversation okay so i have a i have a
short little story i'll share with you
that i think you'll enjoy um
it's just thinking of like things that i
was not open to receiving
five years ago in what i am now you know
um like my
my view on like spirituality and spirit
and soul and um
you know christianity buddhism like all
of these i i just have this like dude i
get what you're pointing at i 100 and i
love that too and that's something that
i point out in myself and some days i
feel like i use this language and some
days i use this this way of saying it
you know and i think it's all beautiful
i love it all and bring on all religions
bring on all you know explanations of
spirit spiritual being like they're all
so fascinating i don't care which ones
the capital t truth which one points to
something within me that lights me up
you know um so so i had
uh is when i was when i was back in town
uh
probably like uh
this was probably like winter maybe it
was like seven or eight months ago or
maybe it was a little longer that
essentially it was uh within a few
months of uh of the breakup of my
long-term relationship
and it was also um
a weekend after or a few days after my
cousin casey had passed away um and i
was at work
and uh you know as
i was listening to you know a lot of
like rom das and alan watts and stuff
just trying to like you know do do my
grieving process um but i was also just
i was very sad um
very heartbroken obviously from from the
passing of my cousin but long-term
like you know this whole last year has
been me kind of like sitting with the
pain in my broken heart and trying to
try to accept that and and move forward
you know um but so i was i was
essentially at a really kind of low spot
and i wasn't my
norm normally when i show up as a
supervisor at work i try
uh don't always get there but i try to
show up as like hey guys what's up like
it's gonna be a great day like i try to
you know have that energy so so it's
effect you know i know that it's um
infectious and um i hadn't done that for
a day or two and i had
one of my employees who was like uh
oh man he had been like 19 or something
uh he's his family very sweet family his
mom actually worked there as well
they're very christian very religious um
so
so serving so uh present like i i really
i really liked that their family i got
along with him well um but he he came in
there i i'm his supervisor and he's a
you know a teenager he he comes in and
he kind of like shuts the door a little
bit behind him and he's like hey uh you
know i just uh
i just i just wanted to to ask if
everything was okay
and i was like i mean that almost like
made me cry right there right and uh
because i was like oh dang was i i'm not
hiding it well enough or whatever
and i was like oh man you know that's so
sweet of you to ask i really appreciate
it you know i'm i'm okay you know i'm
kind of going through some personal
stuff and um and i think i just told him
you know like you know i'm dealing with
a recent breakup and
i did recently lose lose someone in my
family so i'm just kind of you know
going through the motions and processing
it basically and uh and he he gave his
condolences and you know said
some sort of um you know let me know if
you need anything so something endearing
he was very sweet of him he walked out
um and then you know the end of the
shift comes and i was i was really in
that stag spot like that night was i
kept like kind of getting farther and
farther into my own head i was very sad
but it was there was this wall up i
started feeling very numb i was not
feeling emotion i was very like um
disassociative uh incredibly
disassociative
um
and
[__] man
he
i was at home and i was riding
uh and feeling emotionless i was at home
later that night writing and he texted
me
and he literally just says and i see his
name pop up and i thought it was strange
that he texted me at like midnight or
something anyway i was like oh maybe
he's not gonna show up for work tomorrow
and he's letting me know
and he just goes
hey jake
i just wanted to let you know that i'm
praying for you
and
and he said like um you know you know
i'm thinking about you i hope
everything's okay basically but like
that first line i just wanted to let you
know that i'm praying for you and when i
read that
instantly i [__] practically fell to
my knees and started bawling like i i it
was this is the second i read that i was
just
boom
and
if i would have if i would have been
that same situation a few years before
where i'm like i don't believe in that
jesus stuff
like i wouldn't have been able to felt
that beauty in that like that divine
moment of you know i was i had some some
plugs that i needed to take out and i
had some some feelings that i needed to
feel because i was suppressing some [__]
um i had some processing that needed to
be done and i and i cried for a long
time that night for real like um and i
felt i felt emptied out and energized
the next day
um but but anyway i i guess i i wanted
to share that um it was just this like
beautiful moment that i'm so glad that i
um
in a selfish way i'm glad that i'm open
to it now you know because a few years
ago i would have i would have
read that and been casual like thanks
bro see you at work you know
so
yeah i appreciate you sharing that story
the big reason why i always appreciate
when you show
uh your emotional intensity about things
so openly is that we need more strong
men
defining what masculinity can also look
like like i think a lot of people are
misguided on the fact that you know
masculine is supposed to include
patient supportive uh compassionate like
masculine traits are not always strong
brave sturdy stern
um they are meant to include
not the masculine side the masculine
version of
being in your feels that is
all-encompassing femininity has its own
way of encompassing their feelings and
sharing them but masculine does too so i
always appreciate when you share the
fact that
yes men cry
it is a thing
um and
it's just so interesting and something's
been on my mind a lot lately
is how much women have decided
either they've been coerced to or they
feel like they genuinely have to or it's
an unconscious thing that they are
adapting to but women are trying to be
more in their own masculine at this
point and they're also under the belief
that masculine is not showing emotions
and being very uh
disassociative and unconcerned with
other things and not being in their
feminine which is to openly show in
voice emotions as they exist
um i follow a girl i think my name is
madeline moon on instagram and she does
a really good job of sharing reels about
this kind of stuff
but i realized that i need to pay more
attention to this because
it's actually not a compliment in my
life to have people tell me
you're a mystery
i can't read you
um
you are so good at
you know your poker face or whatever
like i'm not necessarily like
i'm just trying to describe that better
but it's been on my mind a lot lately
because i realize i used to openly cry
about things when they hurt me when i
was younger and maybe that's just
because i didn't have the emotional
threshold to hold it back yet
um
but for a time period maybe over the
last decade i feel like i really tried
to work on that and now i'm someone who
can actively hold back my emotions and
my facial reactions and part of that was
part of holding back my physical
reaction was part of the job i had at
one point i was required to
give nothing away as part of
testing behavioral health for children
on the autism spectrum if they were
throwing fits or
hurting me or biting me or things like
that i had to show no visible reaction
that they could feed off of so i know
part of that is conditioning that i did
as part of the job but
regardless
i've had a lot of stuff that has upset
me happened in the last several months
maybe even over the last couple of years
but specifically over the last couple of
months
that i've been founding it increasingly
difficult to actually access people in a
way that i need them like i
am now a person who doesn't
feel comfortable crying in therapy which
is totally okay like i advocate for
people to do that when they're in
therapy with me so it kind of feels like
a double standard i've now created that
i'm actively trying to work out of i'm
trying to
if i feel like i might cry in a moment
even if i'm in like a public place
almost especially if i'm in a public
place
maybe i'm intended to do that maybe that
person is going to randomly show me
kindness and i need to allow myself to
tear up a little bit
and
human to humans show them
maybe they're not upsetting me but my
day has been really upsetting and this
is kind of the last straw and
why do we have to try so hard to
maintain that we're not human and i've
had a hard time not crying when other
people are doing therapy as a therapist
you're not supposed to and i'm not a
licensed therapist i need to disclose
that but i do on my bachelor's level and
i've done psychology
i'm told not to
and i just i i
feel like we need to show for more human
if someone is saying something to you
that is truly heartbreaking
if you're standing there going or
sitting there and you're like yeah
you know that that must be so hard or
whatever i mean that's not the way i
talk it's kind of a very but it's fake
and it's unhelpful and it doesn't really
make them feel like you're connecting
with them and so i try to remind myself
but it's hard to come back from it that
it it's almost flattering when someone
does cry in front of you like in a weird
way it's almost flattering to see that
this person is just kind of like fine
i'm gonna let you see the full extension
of my emotions in this moment
and i'm almost trying to trust you that
you are going to respond
either neutral
or accommodating
because in this moment i am not you know
at my fulfilled mental sanity but you
might be
you know it's it's sharing the weight
even in just a conversation with a
client a stranger a friend a family
member
i feel like that's the conversation that
we should really be having more of and
even just like last night i got really
upset about something and i was at my
grandma's and
i didn't want to [__] cry in front of
her but i knew i was going to if i kept
talking and i was just like it was this
active decision in my head i'm like do i
need this conversation more
or do i need to not cry in front of
someone more
and i ended up not even really getting a
choice i said like three more words and
i started crying and i was like well now
it's all off yeah we've already started
crying it doesn't matter how much right
now because we already started
but that's not the attitude i want to
have and that's not the attitude i think
the general public should have man or
woman or child or
anything we should all just be able to
be in our feelings a little bit and show
emotion even at work i think we should
be taking down that barrier and allowing
everyone to see like we are all human
don't expect teachers to be inhuman
don't expect you know people's life
experiences to not show up
in their life i mean we expect this of
celebrities we expect this of presidents
we expect this of all people and i
honestly think it's separating
i think it's what makes us put people on
a pedestal
and then want us we want to be more like
them because they don't show fear they
don't show
upset
and it's it's corrupting our ability to
connect with others
yeah i think it is because we
we're supposed to cry we're supposed to
experience emotion emotions you know
we really are taught to
uh
i mean suppress for sure
but
we almost see it as like like an overly
emotional reaction oh hello
uh
ryan oh yeah that's awesome i uh i'm
missing my i'm missing my dog every day
of course um
but uh yeah it really is like
like
i think that a lot of conversations if
we allow the crying to happen but not
allow it to um
sometimes you could have a couple
minutes of like an overly emotional when
it comes to two people conversating
about something if you're triggering
each other if you are to the point where
you're crying if you've got something
going on that's just coming up in a
conversation um and you you
you poke that hole and the the crying
starts coming you know it's just like oh
great here it comes whatever it's a
it's not a
i i think that is healthy because it
does it not only points to us that like
hey this thing that's going on that i'm
talking about is important you know it's
clearly important if i'm from if i'm if
i'm crying over i'm feeling something
very strongly about this oh dang maybe
it's more important than i thought maybe
i do feel more strongly about this um
sometimes you could randomly poke poke
around i've had conversations with my
friends um where we're just like we're
bsing we're having maybe this kind of
talk and then it gets personal and then
like suddenly i like my my issues with
self-worth are poked and i'm balling my
eyes out and i'm like what the f
how did this even happen but i felt
comfortable i felt open in a loving
place with me and my friend and you know
within three minutes i'm not crying
anymore and we're laughing and we're you
know on to the next thing but it's uh
it's nothing to be ashamed about to cry
it's nothing to be um ashamed about to
feel human emotion dude like it's what
we're doing here it's this whole thing
absolutely
yeah i
it's hard
i just i it's hard to come to like the
root of like where that was decided
i mean not it's not hard to really
decide where it came to with men i mean
men have been
old
man up since they were like little
and that's unfair but
where we decided like
women as well
need to keep their cards close to their
chest all the time
it's a balance of
of the masculine and the feminine it's
not like just because you're a girl you
need to have 100 feminine energy just
because you're a guy you need to have
100 masculine energy it's like no no if
you're a girl or a guy or if whatever
you whatever you identify as you need to
have masculine balance with feminine
balance and that's what makes like the
human
best version of yourself you know like
yeah like where you're you're not
ignoring ignoring the entire aspects of
yourself where you're not um over
correcting over uh
yeah
i think that's the biggest thing it's
you know we hear we hear the word
balance all the time but when it comes
to the masculine and feminine sides of
each of us because we all have each it
is about balance you know and there's
times to
to be more in your feminine maybe for
longer there's times to be more in your
masculine maybe for longer um but i
think as an overall homeostasis
way of being something to strive for
it's it's a balance between the
knowledge that is brought forth from
from both of these
yeah that you have a solid point and i i
feel like what people fail to realize is
that we choose the people we choose to
be our friends and our partners because
we like their balance of masculine and
feminine and specifically
you know that's how we end up like
in some ways you know an athletic couple
two people who are highly athletic
adventurous thrill seekers
i would argue that in some ways both of
them may be more in their masculine than
their feminine
because that drive that ambition
courage is typically more defined and
that way is more defined as a masculine
trait and if it's something they're both
avidly passionate about and that's where
all their hobbies are they love hiking
they love
the versions
they're both a little bit more and
they're masculine and that's totally
cool and so i think we need to figure
out that you know
we don't just like people because of
their
gender that they look like we're still
looking for people that align
with what we want and how much do we
want how much we enjoy someone being in
their masculine and where they're
feminine and when
um
i don't know i think that's just why
like
couples that we are like how does that
work we don't
realize like what's really going on
underneath the surface and to let her
out of the room
right right yeah i'm not a
yeah
we've got to recognize what we are or
are not looking for like i'm not
i'm not looking for a a woman i want a
woman with with a good you know
masculine side but i'm not looking for a
woman who's going to go fistfight
everybody at the bar every time we go
out you know so
it's about balance right
yeah and
i feel like i gave like an anecdote or
two the last one we did and so i was
like thinking about the one i wanted to
get today because
i eventually want to be like some type
of philosopher i need to like start like
dipping a little bit here a little bit
there yeah yeah hit me
but something about is a concept of you
know when people say
and i've seen it in memes so it's like i
feel like it's commonplace knowledge but
the concept of like what we bring
a metaphorical table
in a friendship in a partnership at work
what have you
what we bring to the metaphorical table
and i started really thinking about this
table like if it were a real table
people were physically bringing gifts
outwardly like carrying [__] in their
arms and setting on the table to
bring to the group
how
you know how we think we would like to
hang out with people who are like us and
why i think we don't actually want that
we just don't realize it
is that
it's boring
and i also feel like
when
if we had a whole group of people
sitting at a table and they all brought
the same things to the table
and nothing new to share like they were
identical matches
it's almost like monopolizing and
hoarding
resources in one space and not sharing
them with other people in a way that
would actually light up everyone the
people receiving these new ideas and
gifts and getting to like discuss them
would be thrilled for the opportunity
and the people sharing them who had
stepped away from the table where
everything was the same would also feel
fulfilled thinking this is so cool
people are actually really enjoying what
i have to share an offer
where they would not have that same
feeling at a table where they're like
yeah no we all brought this okay and you
brought oh we all brought that too cool
um
isn't it half what we have
you know it's kind of just like it would
be such a boring
table to sit at and
i don't know i just
um i had more on that like a whole
little short story
it's a lot to talk about but
i like thinking about it that way like
what
what would we really like to bring to
our friendships into our partnerships
and
we want to bring ourselves certainly
but we also want to bring
i don't know bring an open mind
yeah
we're also just as interested at what
other people are bringing to the table
not just what we provide we need to be
as interested about
what other people can provide to us in
return
otherwise it gets offset the balance
yeah yeah it's not about finding this
and only this it's about finding this
and that too you know it's it really is
kind of like a community uh what way of
thinking i get what you're saying you
know
i was thinking about echo chambers as
you were talking um something like like
we
we want to surround ourselves with
people just like us who are going to
reaffirm our ideas and our beliefs and
what we do and what we think is going on
or whatever um
and then we think the contrast of that
needs to be like a debate club like you
find your arch-nemesis of who believes
the opposite of what you do and and
that's how you interact um or you or you
make them the enemy but i think it's uh
it's not so
black and white i think it's like all
the colors you know it's way more colors
than that it's like it's basically
like it's such a beautiful and
like yes to
you being your authentic self and
bringing exactly that to the table like
that's what the table needs because
we're
we're a collective uh but also but also
having
so so you bring what you have to the
table
and you don't look for an echo chamber
you don't look for more people who have
the exact same things that you're
bringing to the table or we all just
brought you know
plain ruffles and that's what we're
eating for dinner you know we
we
keep in mind
the community we keep in mind everybody
what everybody else might be bringing
and then we really focus in on what we
could bring and we and we own that and
we just be our authentic self whatever
the hell that means i'm still trying to
figure it out um i think i think by by
trying to be authentic i'm instantly
inauthentic so [__] but um yeah i i like
that i like that point mike i i do um i
feel like i i do see what you're
pointing at
with that yeah i mean our our genetics
our dna at like a deep level are already
doing this like our i don't know i think
it's going more popularity like people
know about this but our sense of smell
actually helps us dictate who our most
suitable partner is and it's on an
unconscious level it's the pheromones
that people produce in their sweat and
they're just
existing in their body
um
it is it's determined to try and help us
not procreate with our family whether or
not we know them our sense of smell is
supposedly supposed to pick up on
that and steer us away from it like
we're gonna think their sweat stinks
we're gonna think their breath stinks
because we don't we don't want to be
attracted to them our genetics are like
no
this is not the right one but someone
who has different genetics and this kind
of has components that we're missing as
far as like health
attributes
we should from a sensory standpoint
and probably go undetected
we should be drawn to people who have
our opposites
because that's going to give us
from appropriation angle it's going to
give us the best outcome that's going to
give us the best offspring
and so
i always think about just like in the
middle east like ages how they would
like marry into
other families
for power and keep it in the family line
but before that kind of started or if
that wasn't a thing
people really did have healthy strong
vibrant
offspring because they were allowed to
just go off like people smelled bad back
then like they didn't
they kind of tried to cover it up but
you really got to smell what a person
smelled like when you're only bathing
once a week so
with how much we bathe now all our
perfumes deodorants um i know people who
don't use anything as like a scent on
them but even our homes have a scent and
i feel like
we're almost at a disadvantage now like
unless we really get up and close and
personal with someone's like sweat after
they've worked out and we're giving them
a hug
we don't really have a general sense of
what the people you're around smell like
and our genetics can't play as much of a
role in being like
we
do this person on a genetic level like
they would be a good person too
swap dna with share dna
like i don't know i think about that
sometimes and how i mean our generation
i feel like we're plagued by the idea of
when am i gonna find
mr or mr or mrs right
and i think that i think the pheromone
and the sensory aspect kind of plays a
lot into that more than we realize that
at a very basic level we are at a
disadvantage because of all the sensory
things that corroborate what we would
naturally pick up on
right
right yeah yeah it makes me think about
dating apps like dating apps like that's
what they feel so unnatural i mean
they're great in a lot of ways like some
people have had like so many people have
had success and and met awesome people
through dating apps um and i think
there's there's something awesome about
it but they do feel very unnatural like
uh
like to to not have
the things that build up our intuition
which is you know like our interaction
with pheromones and interaction with
sense in our other four senses um
those those are forgotten about in place
of data in place of algorithms
you know it's like
i don't know it it it is very
interesting and the the pheromone thing
is incredibly interesting as you were
talking about that i was this feels so
corny and if this
if this girl hears this for whatever
reason this is going to be like
embarrassing but um
again back in high school
it's not that bad um but uh i still
remember to this day basically back back
in high school um i i'd like i was
hanging out with this girl for for a
little while um and then i ended up like
completely ghosting her and going back
to my ex because i'm a total [__] but um
but essentially to this day i remember
like there was something about like her
her smell like that's that sounds weird
um and it wasn't like her perfume there
was something that i was it was like the
first time i was very cognizant and i
noticed like uh
like like the the person smell a certain
way you know and it's something that you
know they say is is one of the best um
closely tied to it to our memory it's
something that i literally think about
like as you were talking about that i
literally it was just picturing this
girl like yeah she's smelling good so
it's just this super silly thing but i i
think that when it comes to sense when
it comes to you know pheromones we
we have a a knack for labeling things
good or bad you know i
uh on the weekends here um i've been
working at the um
at lake travis and
we have two bathrooms that have air
conditioning uh but there's a lot lot
code on them and there's a bunch of
people that go throughout the day we're
not supposed to give the the number out
like people are supposed to use the
porta potties that are across the way
and there's this like i can watch people
go to the porta potties and they walk
out or they're about to walk in and
they're so disgusted they're like you
you and they they have like this big
reaction about you know how it smells
and how it's so gross and and all this
stuff and i like to go like i'll go into
those porta-potties and just be like
yeah this is what it [__] smells like
like i'm ex like this makes me
appreciate not having to smell this all
the time you know and so like like just
my mindset being different than those
people i think that we see see when it
comes to sense we see when it we smell
when it comes to sense or damn it
when we smell we label it as good or bad
so quickly and i think we should like
take longer consideration of that i
think you'll just accept that something
smells a certain way and then accept
that you now have a reaction to it it
doesn't have to be oh that's stinky we
need to freak out
yes i agree with you i was just thinking
i was like if i even could just if we
were only allowed three categories
percents
and two of them were good and bad i
would like the third one to be
intriguing
like what is intriguing is it i mean
people i think it leans more towards
good but also it's like even with bad
smells or things that i'm not
particularly like and like i wouldn't
want to smell like that or have my house
smell like that i'm like what is that
like
cooking certain spices i'm like
but wait what
it changed i don't know like smells so
important in how we like dictate things
um
the other thing i was thinking about
when we were talking about online dating
and i wanted to let you finish your
whole train of thought was that
i again had thought i'd come up with an
idea that no one else had thought of and
was wrong
but i
my best friend like do you think someone
would use a dating
where you are
you're blind dating yourself like you're
not blind dating yourself but you have
entered into blind dating no one's
entered you into it or no one's set you
up you're setting yourself up on a blind
date
so there are no pictures you get to know
the person's name you get to know their
age you get to know like where they live
locationally because that is important
and then they just have to you have to
spend time writing an intricate bio that
kind of showcases your personality your
humor some of your interests maybe your
astrology sign
but there are no photos so you go
through people's profiles and you're
just like you're reading like a story
you're actually just reading the story
you don't get to see a picture so you
don't have to decide
i don't know i just i feel like i've not
had success on dating apps because i
date i on dating apps i'm shallow
if i
it's an energy exchange like it does not
matter how attractive i find you if i
can't have a 30-minute conversation with
you in a bar and feel like i'm generally
interested or wherever i am
this won't be happening like i won't be
doing this again as intimately i've
already learned that we don't really
vibe on a conversational level
um
so i was like it was almost like a way
to like protect me from myself if i
really had to just look at a way a
person spoke
and
you know even just look at their grammar
and look at the jokes they try to make
and what their interests are i think i
would be much more likely to set myself
up with someone who would be good for me
or who would become a friend they would
have enough in common it wasn't a
romantic attraction i at least gave a
chance on meeting a new friend
um and she said there's a tv show i
leo also i'd have to like look it up
again but i like need to watch it
because she's like this already exists
but yes i do think people would use it
um
because i really just thought about it
you know i've had i've had four
significant relationships in my life
uh romantic relationships and
with the exception of one of them which
was my first one which is just like that
head over heels naive you know you just
you see someone and you're like oh my
god i'm in love you know whatever so
we're gonna exclude that one but the
other three
i did not i did not think they were the
most handsome men i'd ever seen i
wouldn't even think they were in like
the top five and so now if they hear
this i'm gonna be like you know what i
probably do
i don't care they'll never know which
one who's what
but i just i really and even as i
started to enter into a relationship
with them i realized i did not find them
physically attracted like i as as i had
you know my one night stands or anyone
else i found their personality
attractive i found their humor i found
their smile i found their laugh i found
their energy attractive and i really was
in these relationships because i
genuinely found the person at a deeper
soul level attractive
and i thought that was cool like when i
really sit with that i it gives me a
chance to realize i'm not inherently a
shallow person
i'm not dating someone for stature power
looks aesthetics any of that i'm
picking people that i really date and
connect to for a deeper reason
but it also makes me realize
why am i not doing that in my dating
life like if i don't if i'm not meeting
people organically and i'm just trying
to meet new people why am i not more
open about
yeah this person doesn't strike me as
like the most attractive that i've come
across in my last seven swipes but
their bio is funny why would i not swipe
right just because they have a clear
sense of humor through the computer or
the phone mm-hmm
i
thinks about that and processes on that
too that how unfair we're actually being
to ourselves and giving our chance
giving ourselves a chance at having
efficient and successful relationships
because of how we're meeting people now
is more superficial it's more shallow
we're looking at pictures
we're not getting to look at a person
and there's no way we're getting to feel
a person through the phone it's just not
a thing
um
i just feel like in a lot of respect
we're not giving ourselves a
getting ourselves a
connect with people
and the more try to connect with that we
probably knew from the start that we
didn't have a lot in common with or they
weren't particularly on the same
or level with us
we become discouraged we're like oh i've
gone on you know five tinder dates and
they're all just boring or they're all
just aggressive or because we're not
looking for the right things when we're
on the app we're doing it to ourselves
like our intuition could pick up on
something but our eyes are
you know leading the service
yeah
i 100 agree i
yeah my my
it is very interesting to treat
an entire
like like when i scroll through tinder
you're literally just saying yes or no
it's like you're treating a person as a
one or a zero and it is just you're
playing the game with the game pieces
right like there there is like like
there's a part of me that wants to feel
like shame about that you know i'm like
i'm [__] shallow and that's [__] up
and whatever but
i i think that it is it is part of the
game like let's don't don't [__]
yourself that um that that isn't there
is more that can come out of tinder and
that's not the only side of it but that
is kind of the basics of it is if you
know when you're scrolling there you're
getting your yeses in in your nose like
like i find this girl this this girl or
guy attractive or i do not find this
girl or guy attractive um and it is
frustrating to me too micah that i
i will pick like like their interest in
their their bio
i'm like yeah i would like that person
but i'm not physically attracted to them
and it'll be a no for me and then and
i'm sitting there like what am i what am
i looking for you know it so so maybe
maybe i'm sure not everybody has this
exact same experience uh with with
dating apps um but i think
as i've as i've been on it for a few
months
and i'm i'm on it less and less i like
it less and less um
i i think that going into tinder knowing
what you want is
huge
meaning if i was going into tenor
knowing that i'm looking up like i'm
looking for hookups like i'm knowing
that i'm just i'm just looking for you
know a little bit of fun on a friday
saturday night like let's let's both
have a great time mutual we don't have
to talk after what i don't know how this
really goes i haven't had any any um
actual experience in it but uh like
there there is a difference between
going in like that
um knowing that it's just a hookup going
in for looking for a relationship like
hey i'm i'm this many years old and i'm
looking to settle down i'm looking to
find someone who has the same interest
in me and i really want to hit it off
because i'm looking to get married like
that's a huge difference between looking
to hook up and then where i'm at where i
just don't know like i just
i
like i i'm open to what whatever is
going to happen i don't know that i have
i'm like have a ton of time to be
emotionally available you know um but
but i i don't want to shield myself off
i do enjoy talking to to an attractive
you know i i like flirting back and
forth between between someone that i
find attractive and finds me attractive
of course like don't [__] deny that
um
but yeah so i i think overall what i'm
saying is
not knowing what you're trying to get
out of tinder out of dating apps or what
not knowing what you really want out of
dating
is it
puts handcuffs on you in in a strange
way um
but yeah i don't know what you you
jotted something down what what do you
got micah i'm just rambling about my
weird
think about what you were saying
um so i was thinking about
kind of changing my idea or maybe like
adding more stuff to it but what if we
instead of yes or no which is so simple
the checkmark or
you know
doing a scale like what if we were able
to join apps and then there were two
scales like we have on instagram one
below the other and we could slide it
um and one could be the platonic scale
see if you're only there for friends
maybe you only acknowledge that one and
you just completely ignore the other
scale being
romantic or attractive too
like the physical attraction and you can
just move one like if you want to make
friends you could just move the platonic
one too like hey it seems like we have
lots in common let's hang out or
um i'd just like to talk to you online
um and like maybe we could like slide to
a scale
and then when we give that input when
someone slides on
we get to decide whether or not we slide
back and meet them at the same point
like i completely agree
or
if we want to like change it a little
bit if we did find them attractive like
also in turn with like you wanting to
friends i do find you attractive like
could there be more is there open
like
there's it so many things are a
continuum and i wonder if a team profile
should just adopt that idea like
why are you why are you on the app and
how are you viewing this person not just
check mark vibrate
like that's so ambiguous what does it
really mean
why
right on this person what was it that
did it for me
it is it is weird to think about the
the contrast between
someone who is just a friend and someone
who who is a friend that you would like
to have romantic relationship with
though because i think that
like the second you make that an okay
door to explore it changes your
interaction with that person like
because you know when we're thinking out
of you know like our our horny ape minds
where
we we think differently like like
there's this saying you've probably
heard it before uh like a guy will
decide if he would sleep with a woman
within the first 10 seconds of meeting
her or something like that have you
heard that before
the box theory yeah the box oh there's a
whole theory on yeah so i've casually
heard it you may be able to explain it
better than i can but it really uh i
mean there is there is something to it
like as is as gross as that feels to
admit you know
it is something that's like
a real thing you know like i i don't
know that there there is a different
um there's a different side of ourselves
again as much as i wouldn't want to
admit it if
i'm meeting a girl for the first time
and i think there's you know like like
we're meeting on a level of hey you're
single and i'm single and like let's
kind of flirt i'm going to have a
different you know day of conversation
with her than
if if she if she is married right like
if she that same situation like even if
i thought she was attractive but if she
was married if that's and that's a line
that i would obviously draw for myself
like i'm going to show up as a different
a different person so there's almost
like these blockages psychologically
that we put up on ourselves um
that stopped the
the naturalness of it but yeah i don't
know dating apps
i i think it would have to be a whole
new thing like if we took on your idea i
think it would have to be it wouldn't
just be like and tinder's doing this now
because people would
people want their yeses or no's they
want their like
can i get laid or not get laid or can i
can i
can this person become my wife or is
there no potential of that you know gosh
and i don't feel like it would be
particularly popular if we set it up at
the very beginning
where they had to decide and select an
option like just here to hook up could
be its own like pool of people like at
the very opening when you like create
your profile here's my name here's my
phone number
whatever that the very next step is
why do you want like how do you want to
use this app one pool for
just here for hookups
one pool of people for looking for
friends
not emotionally available
and then another
for
i would like something deeper
i'm here to date i'm here to go on dates
i'm here to find relationships intimate
romantic relationship
but i think a lot of people when they
start on a dating app they
i i'm guilty of it too more or less i
just want to go on there and see what's
out there i don't really know i don't
want to like agree to just one thing
like i kind of just want to see what's
available before i make my decision as
to what category i would put someone in
but that's the problem
that is the problem we need to go in
there with an idea of what we want like
you're saying other
we have all these weird rules and
yeah i
i i think of dude i do weird [__] dating
apps are so weird uh it's like the
weirdest side of myself to to to learn
about um i'll do this thing like i'll
match with girls
and like like my and i'll never message
them you know like i'll never say
anything like i have there's just tons
of girls that are just
and then it gets a couple days later and
i'm like well now it's [__] too late
like i i miss that so then i'm wondering
like what am i doing like when i'm
scrolling like i'm scrolling through
here or um like like i got the uh i i
paid for the the version again shame um
like so i get notified when someone
likes me and i could say say yes or no
and all like all like oh yeah that
girl's cute like oh she likes yoga she
likes philosophy she likes trail right
like cool let's let's talk and and i'll
say yeah cool she's cute and then like
it'll just sit there like i don't talk
to her i don't and and i there there's a
lot of me that kind of
i i think that i'm too cool or i go to
meta on like the like i don't want to do
the opening line
corny you know dad joke thing and then
there's other sides of me where i'm like
i get that that's how you play the game
though like literally that's how humans
work if you can make someone laugh you
kind of have an opening and then you
know they're comfortable with you or
whatever it becomes for you know
we're laughing together rather than
complete strangers that's a huge line
broken down so i don't know i don't know
mike i don't know what i'm talking about
or saying but
tinder and dating apps are [__] weird
yeah you're on to something though it is
it's do you want to play the game or
not play the game and if you don't want
to play the game dating apps will not
work for you
dating apps don't work for me because i
don't want to play
i just want i don't know my big request
on dating apps is i'm like hit me with
an open-ended interesting question
i've got
completely ignored people who start with
hey
what's up
how are you i am i i'm like i undo it
see but that's that's [__] because
it's hard to know on on the guy's end
because like some girls they want that
and you can't really always tell just
from like there like sometimes you're
like okay maybe this girl is more into
like this like this girl looks like she
wants dad jokes or because of her bio
saying this it's this like we're
constantly trying to analyze like uh
i have had i i've had girls message me
first
and they'll like they're like hey you
with a smiley face and i'm like hey
what's up smiley face and it's not
ghosted like it's nothing like i didn't
say the correct thing back like oh [__]
was i supposed to that's when i was
supposed to said that dad joke that i
googled
yesterday you know or whatever it was
like it's just so [__] calculated i
don't know how to be natural about it
i agree with you but i do i try to be
fair i put it on my bio i use hinge and
i put it on my bio like the way to get
to know me is asking open ended
interesting questions like i i put it
right there but i guess it doesn't say
you know explicitly if you enter in the
conversation
boring ass small talk
people won't even do your thought you
know but
i guess
like a little speak we don't like we
don't really care if we make connection
or not on social media all it would take
is me one
remotely interesting decent person
in person i probably wouldn't hit our
app for like a week we would just talk
to that person through text instead and
hang out with them and give them a
chance i don't think anyone actually
expects a lot out of dating apps i know
i know i don't
yeah i i met a guy um
the last show that i worked in florida
uh we were talking about like because i
hadn't seen everybody in a while and
they're like what's been up like how are
you how's austin like have you gotten
the dating apps yet you know like my
homies are like how you doing in the
dating room um in in one of the one of
the camera operators chimed in and he's
like i actually met my wife on tinder um
and they're they're very happy and he
said what he did like he was at a point
where he was he was ready to get married
he wanted a wife like um which which i
feel like is like a actually like that
that's a pretty cool place to be like
you know what yeah i'm ready for this
this is what i want like i know what i'm
looking for um and he said i think he
said he just started like
he started just swiping yes on everybody
like if they he thought they were
interesting at all or or they had
anything in common whatever he would
just open up a conversation and he would
just spend some time talking to
everybody and like the ones that he
spent more time with you know and he
ends up like he met his wife on there
it's just because they had great
conversation back and forth because he
was very open to like
just just say yes to everybody and let's
have conversations and see where it goes
you know that seems like a lot of effort
that seems like so much time spent
like
like i i this sounds so selfish but i
think i value my my time too much to
to have that many conversations going on
it's he sounds like a wonderful person
just from like the amount of effort he
was willing to put forward and for his
own intrinsic motivation like no one
expected him to he's just like you know
what let me give everyone a shot yeah
you know like that's
smart
he knew what his was and he knew that it
meant
you know getting rid of some of his
stigmas and biases
yeah yeah i mean i don't know uh i don't
know him very well we just like he just
was chiming in on our conversation uh
but i will say he's a fantastic jib
camera operator as well so he's got that
going for him for him just the same
yeah so uh
michael we're getting kind of up here in
time and i do need to get ready for work
shortly so um
let's let's kind of round the corner i
was thinking about like you know a lot
of times i'll ask at the end of the
podcast i'll ask like what does the
world need more of right now um or i'll
ask something like specific that i that
i thought of through through the
conversation that like might just
interact with that person uh what i'd
like to ask of you micah i feel like
you probably know
you know you know
a good amount of people who might listen
to to the podcast or or what the type is
like we grew up in the same town um
you've been on the podcast you kind of
know like my style and what i like to
talk about and stuff um
like as an ending wrap-up
section or question like what
if you were talking to the listeners or
or someone who needed to hear something
right now like what do you what's like a
message or a piece of advice
or something that maybe like a blanket
statement that you might be able to
offer listeners like
um that might might help them out might
give them different perspective
might uh it might just be something
you're personally experiencing now
that's just helpful to offer others i
don't know do you have anything when i
when i when i ask that micah
my cat keeps butting the door open and
closed
can't decide
he's distracting she's
too much um
make a statement
i am
i'm struggling with the super uh
wide range of
the ways i could answer questions um
i also have to admit i haven't really
been feeling like much of myself lately
so i'm struggling to just like
throw something together with a lot of
nash and
mica authenticity
but i guess something i've been thinking
a lot lately about is
i struggle with it it's
feeling like i am
i'm considering what other people's
motivations are without actually asking
them
like
i'm assuming i know why people are doing
the things that they're doing
without actually
opening up the dialogue to them and
it's hard to have conversations like
this even for someone like me that
advocates for people having them
um
i'm feeling this way
in response to
you know our last conversation or our
interactions lately or the lack of
communication between us and
i'm just curious as to
if you have stuff in your life going on
that
is affecting our relationship
um
but if i could just if you could i don't
know just basically explain what's going
on so i don't feel like it's a direct
attack on
our friendship or you're not wanting to
spend time with me
um
so i don't know that's i mean that's
been on my mind a lot it's not a blanket
statement really it's just
if before we go ahead and get upset
about
something that's not happening or
something that is happening
we can't just assume that we know that
everyone involved in that thought
understands what's happening
can we really be
more
with other people and be like i'm
feeling this way
and i just wondered if you were picking
up on it or if there's
there's a reason behind how i'm feeling
if you can provide more perspective
because if anything involves another
person that way
um
we don't have the whole story by just
trying to like demystify it and think it
through in our own mind what may or may
happening in that connection
we then always we have answers in our
own mind but if it involves another
person we really don't
yeah we have a lot of ways of jumping to
conclusions in our own head cavity you
know assuming the person is doing this
or purposely doing that um you know and
a lot of times i think that we'll find
when you do have that straight up
conversation send that long text send
that whatever or
just maybe one sentence text and just
ask what's up um
uh
yeah i i think we find that a lot of
times it's not personal you know it's
it's not
if if there is distance between us if
there is distance between
um
[Music]
you know if if there's
it's not ill intent a lot of the times
maybe it could be so it is worth asking
maybe maybe what you have what you're
thinking about it does have validity to
it don't just disregard it you know
think about it but
yeah i i think uh
not
not assuming before talking right
yeah and being open
to the idea
of just
believing what they say their intent is
like unless your intuition and your gut
is like
very in a big way saying the opposite
um just
being willing to believe them if they
have some sort of reason even if it's
like an excuse that that is why
this one thing in their life is
affecting their friendships
and we wouldn't have known how to ask
them
so yeah i don't know just being
a better listener than we are a speaker
this is something that's in turn
i feel like
has made me want to listen more
because i actually don't want to speak
so that's the only other option if i
want to be a part of that interaction is
okay
i'll listen this time
yeah okay okay i like it well micah
thanks for um answering my
my like very on the spot uh think of
something and make it important
questions i i like i feel so terrible
sometimes i'll hear myself rambling
around the question and before i even
get to the end i'm like oh i'm screwing
this person over
i'm like setting them up up for failure
but you certainly did not fail um i
think you pointed out something that
that a lot of us deal with so so thank
you for uh
for being being vulnerable and finding
something in your personal life to to
share with others
all right thank you for having me i wish
you were not texas i wish we could be
doing this in person but
um if anything doing this podcast has
just made me even more certain
that
a visit needs to happen in the future
a visit i've never been to texas so that
would be fun but it's great come on down
i i like it so far i'm moving into my
new apartment next monday actually so
just a few days so i'll have my own spot
so feel free to come down whenever mike
i'll also be down um i'll text you about
it i'll be down sometime in in november
so i think we may be able to find some
time to to go for a walk or something so
perfect sounds great
yeah yeah thank you micah listeners take
care of yourself love yourself um if you
want to check out the other episode with
micah feel free um mike has a couple
things that she's written too so you can
maybe check those out and search for
them maybe it'll be a mystery for you to
find um
yeah again thank you micah take care
love yourselves peace out
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
foreign
knowledge is power
[Music]
you